Spire

A spire is a body of terrain extending to an abnormal altitude from the mountainous plane of Marlien. Strictly the term is applied only to those which hold at least one moon, star, or Planet in their orbit (even if that orbit is shared with other spires), but significant extentions of the Marlien's terrain which lack any satelites have also been described as spires for lack of a better term. Otherwise, there is no defined height or gravitational factor which identifies between a mountain of the plane, or a spire.

Common Features

Water Cycle

On spires warmed by a nearby sun it is common for water to melt from the frozen mountains about the curving base, flowing gradually down the spire, eventually evaporating or reaching the tip, where it flows off in a stream. Water flowing away from the tip eventually evaporates, and evaporated water from the tip or otherwise flows northward on solar winds, towards the plane. The water vapour then condenses and falls back to the spire, or to the plane.

Structure

Typically the base of a spire is curved, gradually leveling out with the surrounding terrain of the plane (allowing for the mountains, of course). Gravity adjusts gradually, following this curve until it eventually pulls towards the plane itself.

The tip and core of most spires consists of an incredibly dense, tough material, neither metal nor stone, encasing a molten core with veins connecting to the Marlien itself. The density of matter increases gradually on the approach to the tip, as the depth of the inner shell decreases, and the tip of most spires is impervious to damage from any man-made tools.

Great Spires

Great spires are those which are abnormally large - usually large enough to sustain orbiting bodies far beyond their own atmosphere.

List of Spires

Spires

Naltera

Gunnl

Great Spires

Dajoxin

Xiexio

Xiexio (she-shö) is the abbreviated name of the Xienonxionin (She-non-shö-nin), also named Xeno or Zeno by the phonetic translation of their hieroglyphs by some Naltera scholars. The Xienonxionin are a race of technologically advanced, four-armed humanoids uniquely native to Thexingja.

Jinxi Telekinesis

Whether by natural evolution, the product of genetic manipulation, or a deliberate mutation influenced by some outsider, Xienonxionin and some other creatures native to Thexingja posses the innate ability to manipulate kinesis-sensitive materials such as Jinxi via telekinesis. As a result, many Xiexio technologies, tools, vehicles, etc. accommodate hands-free operation by integration of Jinxi. It is cheap enough on Thexingja to add sufficient quantities of Jinxi to most small tools and arms, to produce jewelery and even clothing laced with the material. Many of the smaller xiexio vehicles, including one-man Spacecraft are built using sufficient quantities of Jinxi to allow telekinetic rearrangement of modules, and even piloting, though the Xiexio prefer to build a projected, haptic interface into important machines in case of circumstances which interfere with the use of telekinesis.

Typically military vehicles, weapons and arms designed for use around hostile Xienonxionin do not utilise Jinxi, as it leaves such tools open to outside influence. Modular personal Spacecraft which rely heavily on Jinxi manipulation usually include a system of tethers which can be manually locked in place from the cockpit, preventing external sabotage.

Appearance

Xienonxionin are of roughly human stature and build, tending to be shorter on average, and slight or athletic rather than muscular - though their range of builds is as extreme as it may be among humans. The first pair of arms is located where a human's would be, while the second extend from an additional pair of shoulders just below and behind the first. They have a deep, somewhat dull pink or purple complexion, ranging through to pale blue tones in some regions of Thexingja. Their hair, typically adorned with Jinxi beads, is most naturally a purple or blue colour darker than the skin, fading to a silver-gray with age; lighter shades of blue, even almost white, are also found naturally, and teal hair is a somewhat rare occurrence.

Facially, Xienonxionin vary from region to region, but to a human of Naltera, the notable differences in face shape are a tendency towards narrow noses, large lips, and lobeless ears which are sometimes pointed, and sometimes like small circles. Furthermore, where a human would have eyebrows a Xienonxionin appears to have a row of spherical stones set into the brow; though hard and solid these are actually formed from the same material as the hair, and so share its colour. The number of these stones varies from person to person but is usually between 3 and 5, with the stones nearer to the centre being on average the largest.

Culture

Xienonxionin culture varies around the globe, but the dominant culture is a heavily class-based, communist meritocracy ruled by a a high council composed of the leaders from all nations of Thexingja, including those who otherwise distance themselves from the global culture. Personal humility and respect of one's superiors is a general point of importance, though an individual's standing is more flexible than in many cultures, being strongly swayed by the current situation - an aristocrat will often bow before his tailor, dressmaker, bodyguard, etc. when he is pleased with their work, or has an awkward request. As a result, interactions between Xienonxionin may appear erratic to other races, with each participant fluctuating between different levels of respectfulness and flippancy. This is worsenned by the fact that other races typically only deal with council officials and spacers, whose close standing, differing roles, and exposure to other cultures often makes for a lack of social precedent.

In most Xienonxionin cultures individuals of high standing wear loose-fitting robes with no specific sleeves cut and paint their faces with heavy make-up in traditional styles. Robes and other garments, as with hair, are often laced with Jinxi to allow for telekinetic control. Those in active occupations, such as spacers, often wear tighter-fitting garments. Lower classes of Xiexio, or those in roles requiring physical activity, often cut their hair short, while others tie it into ornate knots with the aid of their telekinesis. Messy or free-flowing hair may be seen as a sign of stupidity, laziness, lack of pride, or disregard for others.

Adventurers

Xienonxionin do not make a habit of journeying off world, but those who do are usually spacers. Their society upon Thexingja is advanced enough that true adventuring is not common amongst the inner cities; open spaces are easily surveyed with the aid of long-range vehicles, so only the deepest jungles and most imposing terrain on the fringes of civilization remain to be explored.

Spacers

A much varied profession captured under one title; Spacers operate under the authority of the Spacers' Guild, which although technically beneath the council operates independently of it, and could easily oppose it in military might. Open conflict or espionage, however, is in the interests of neither party.

Agents of the Spacers' Guild include merchants traveling to what few distant places the Xienonxionin openly trade with, Pioneers who explore the far reaches of space to gather information for scientific and navigational purposes, Shepherds who police trade routes and space within the Xiexio territories, and Sheriffs or Special Agents, who travel throughout Xiexio space and distant places, usually alone or in pairs, to pursue the interests of the Council or Spacer's Guild in the name of peace-keeping.

The hierarchy of the Spacer's Guild is complex, with the lowest ranks being mercenary and ill-defined in role, but a clear upper echelon and system of promotion beyond that. Almost anyone can get a Spacer's license and begin to operate as a mercenary Spacer, but they are similarly easily dismissed at such a low rank.

At higher ranks individuals will begin to see the gears of guild politics in motion as their orders from their superiors begin to conflict with those of the council. Even a high-ranking Sheriff is duty-bound to follow the orders of the lowliest Council official, though that official must lean on the support of his superiors if the guild as an entity questions those orders. In most cases this level of politicking is taken care of by the guild directors and high counselors themselves, or a dissenting member of either organisation will clearly hold no sway over an agent's actions, but on occasion, a guild agent recieving opposing orders will be left in the lurch, having to muster what support they can to do what they believe is right.

Mage Technicians

In the Creation Marlien, practitioners of the arcane arts are not common among the Xiexio, with the majority of such being naturally-gifted sorcerers who practice mental discipline in order to direct their energies. Such practitioners have a high standing in Xiexio society, since their technology in Marlien is based upon arcane principles, and their batteries charged with magical energy.

Production teams for Xiexio computer technology, advanced mechanics, Spacecraft, weapons systems, and so on, are a mix of pure technicians, who are often more the more skilled, and mage technicians, who are necessary for advanced technologies. Technologies are designed specifically to be safe and usable by anyone, regardless of magical ability.

Few Xiexio work as dedicated battery chargers as they once might have in small villages, because there are limits to even the most talented channeller's daily potential. For larger communities Ritual Plants are usually set up with an infrastructure which provides energy to all surrounding buildings and sites; once activated by a group of Mage Technicians, such a site requires only one or two to monitor and maintain it over its lifespan. Mages who wish to make a little extra income may sometimes add themelves to a public directory so that others may come to them for a cheap top-up.

Council

Composed of the leaders of every nation on Thexingja, including those who choose to remain isolated from the larger Xienonxionin culture, the High Council dictates global policy, and instructs Xienonxionin affairs off-world, usually in coordination with the Spacer's Guild.

Besides the national leaders, selected by whatever the preferred means are of each, the High Council employs a large number of clerks and career politicians.

Male Names

Anlo, Anfen, Ban, Bofen, Haiso, Jailan, Ji, Juwan, Joa, Kaia, Li, Lofa, Minam, Silu, Taifen, Taiwen, Xin, Xiofen, Xiowen

Female Names

Aila, Ain, Aing, Aixa, Boxi, Chia, Fei, Gia, Jailan, Jaixia, Jinxi, Juchu, Kia, Lai, Li, Lina, Lulu, Minam, Nala, Nana, Nien, Nioa, Xei, Xiedoa, Xiuyin

Stats

Table: Random Height and Weight

Gender | Base Height | Height Modifier | Base Weight | Weight Modifier
Male | 4 ft. 2 in. | +2d10 in. (4 ft. 4 in. - 5 ft. 10 in.) | 75 lbs. | + 2d8x5 lbs. (85 lbs. - 155 lbs.)
Female | 4 ft. 0 in. | +2d10 in. (4 ft. 2 in. - 5 ft. 8 in.) | 70 lbs. | + 2d8x5 lbs. (80 lbs. - 150 lbs.)

Racial Traits

Ability Score Racial Traits

Xiexio are nimble and keen-minded, but the light frames which allow them to lift their own weight through Jinxi telekinesis are weak and easily damaged.

-2 Strength

+2 Dexterity

-2 Constitution

+2 Wisdom

Jinxi Telekinesis

Xiexio may manipulate any object of sufficient Jinxi content as described under the general rules of Jinxi Telekinesis. Objects may be moved as subtly as through controlled by hand, through movements of heavier objects will be likewise clumsy. Unless otherwise stated, all abilities resulting from this trait, including Returning Weapons, have a maximum range of 20ft.

Xiexio Proficiency

Xiexio do not automatically gain proficiency with any weapon with “Xiexio Advanced” in the name, but treat any weapon with “Xiexio Martial” in the name as a martial weapon, and automatically gain proficiency with any other weapon with “Xiexio” in the name.

Racial Feats

Far-reacher

With training, a Xiexio may learn to increase the range of their Jinxi Telekinesis up to 40ft.

Heavy-lifter

With training, a Xiexio may learn to control greater quantities of Jinxi, increasing the upper limit in each category of their Jinxi operation potential by 2 lbs.

Xiexio Special Equipment

Weapons

Xiexio Shock Staff

A Quarterstaff built to release a stunning jolt of arcane energy when it strikes an opponent. Functions as though it has the Merciful magic weapon special ability, but without any bonus.

As with any weapon not dependent upon telekinesis, a shock staff may be built with or without Jinxi.

| Weight | Cost
Shock Staff | 6 lbs | 200 gp
Shock Staff (No Jinxi) | 5 lbs | 195 gp

Xiexio Martial Multilance

The multilance is an outdated weapon designed to be wielded by a group of Xiexio in order to overwhelm the opposition with projectiles such that they cannot be easily caught with the same telekinesis used to throw them. It has sustained some use in the modern world as a tool for hunting cetain game, and has re-emerged as a weapon wielded by renegade Xiexio against aliens without Jinxi telekinesis.

The weapon itself is a heavy, jinxi laced, spear which is designed to separate into three separate projectiles mid-flight. It may therefore be thrown as one projectile, or manually divided and thrown piece by piece.

| Dmg | Type | Weight | Cost
Multilance Third | 3d6 | P | 4 lbs. | 5 gp
Multilance Whole | 1d8 | P | 12 lbs. | 12 gp

Xiexio Martial Disruptor Pistol

Xiexio Advanced Disruptor Rifle

Xiexio Advanced Disruptor Lance

The disruptor lance is a weapon often attached to personal Spacecraft, and occasionally wielded as a heavy weapon, with one or more lances hovering over the shoulder of an individual. It fires a concentrated beam of arcane energy like that of a Disruptor Pistol, but stronger.

| Weight | Cost
Disruptor Lance | 60 lbs | 400 gp
Disruptor Lance (No Jinxi) | 50 lbs | 350 gp

Armour

Modular Armour

Modular armour is embedded with Jinxi and composed of layered scales with multi-purpose links to keep it together when at rest. A Xiexio wearing this armour, or other creature capable of manipulating Jinxi via Telekinesis, gains a +2 bonus to their AC unless they are somehow denied their telekinetic ability, or Dexterity bonus to AC, or are caught unaware of the attack. Any medium or heavy armour may be made into modular armour; for the price increase, see the table of jinxi cost, based upon weight of the armour.

Xiexio Fabrics

The advanced technologies of the Xeixio allow for the production of lightweight, flexible, and yet durable materials, which provide some protection without restricting the movements of the wearer.

This allows for a special armour category, No Armours, which do not require proficiency, or count as armour for monks or those with similar features.

No Armours
Armour | Cost | Armour/Shield Bonus | Maxmimum Dex Bonus | Armour Check Penalty | Arcane Spell Failure Chance | Speed | Weight
30 ft. | 20 ft.
Xipao Skinsuit | 100 gp | +1 | - | 0 | 0% | 30 ft. | 20 ft. | 5 lbs.
Xipao Robes | 150 gp | +2 | +8 | 0 | 0% | 30 ft. | 20 ft. | 6 lbs.

Light Armours
Armour | Cost | Armour/Shield Bonus | Maxmimum Dex Bonus | Armour Check Penalty | Arcane Spell Failure Chance | Speed | Weight
30 ft. | 20 ft.
Guardsuit | 150 gp | +3 | +8 | -1 | 5% | 30 ft. | 20 ft. | 10 lbs.
Armoured Xipao Coat | 200 gp | +4 | +6 | -1 | 10% | 30 ft. | 20 ft. | 15 lbs.

Medium Armours
Armour | Cost | Armour/Shield Bonus | Maxmimum Dex Bonus | Armour Check Penalty | Arcane Spell Failure Chance | Speed | Weight
30 ft. | 20 ft.
Platecoat | | | | | | | |
Platesuit | | | | | | | |

Shields

Orbitals

Orbitals are a form of hands-free physical shield designed to require as little manual guidance as possible. A creature capable of controlling Jinxi may cause a number of Orbitals equal to their Wisdom bonus (max 4) to orbit their body. Orbitals may be grasped and thrown, or thrown using telekinesis, but they are treated as an improvised weapon, dealing damage appropriate for the size (1 S, 1d2 M, etc.).

Actions such as deploying orbitals, halting or resuming their orbit, require a move action, but multiple may be affected at once.

A creature wielding orbitals gains AC and takes an obscuring penalty to sight-based perception checks and all ranged or melee attacks per active orbital.

Bladed Orbitals

1d2 S, 1d3 M

P

monk

Bladed orbitals are a type of light orbital favoured by Xiexio monks, modified to serve as viable weapons. They are not treated as improvised weapons when thrown and may be used for melee attacks without provoking attacks of opportunity.

Orbitals | Dmg (M) | Type | AC Bonus | Obscuring Penalty | Weight | Cost
Light | 1d2 | B | +0.5 | -0.5 | 3 lbs. | 6 gp
Heavy | 1d2 | B | +1 | -1 | 6 lbs. | 14 gp
Bladed, Light | 1d3 | P | +0.5 | -0.5 | 2 lbs. | 10 gp

Other

Orbital Belt

An orbital belt is a simple accessory typically worn around the waist or across the torso, with slots to accomodate up to four light, or two heavy Orbitals.

Orbital Harness

Sometimes called a Beetle Harness, because of its appearance when supporting a full compliment of heavy Orbitals, an orbital harness is usually designed to be worn over the torso, with slots down the back or spine which can accommodate up to four light or heavy Orbitals. Sometimes a harness is built into the back of medium or heavy armour.

Godmage Vinewyltt

Vinewyltt was the founder and absolute ruler of Uubvine for the entire duration of its existance. He was an unrivalled practitioner of the arcane arts, a virtually-immortal human, creator of various Chimera, and considered a deity by his Uubvine subjects.

Vinewyltt's assumed end came with his initiation, deliberate or not, and possibly also termination of, the First North Sea Fiend Storm.

Works

Uubvine

It is not known whether Vinewyltt set out to found the vast city that his following became, but in his prime the Godmage embraced his function as a national and spiritual leader, though less comfortable as a subject of worship.

Creatures

One of Vinewyltt's favoured pastimes and avenues of research was in the keeping of exotic creatures, bending them to his will, and experimentation in creating new species. Through his experiments he created countless unique creatures, some breeds of which far outlasted their creator:

Vinewyltt's Chimeras

Vinewyltt's Hydra

juba_bird

The Fiend Storm

Life

Origins

In legends, Vinewyltt was already far older at the start of the golden_age than any man should see, having already unlocked the secrets of eternal life.

Downfall

In the later part of the golden_age Vinewyltt became increasingly obsessed with unlocking the utmost secrets of the universe, perhaps spurred on by discovery of some ancient Graadien or by the Magefiend. Because of this his later creations were often foul and destructive without apparent reason, but such as the awe with which the people of Uubvine beheld him that their faith did not waver.

Depictions of Charon appear in numerous late and post-Graadien works, including the great Yamaraj which may or may not have partaken in the sacking. Some artefacts indicate that the Graadien mages were visited numerous times by agents of the Charon, warning them to desist from the deployment of their soul_bomb.

Vinewyltt gathered, and rightly so, that these agents were otherworldly beings who might posses secret understandings of the universe far beyond what he had so far comprehended, and so he desired an audience with them himself. The only records he could find of them, however, were the fleeting depictions in Graadien artefacts, and so he sought to mimic their method of gaining the Charon's ear: the ever escalating application of arcane energies.

It is possible that Vinewyltt's Cockatrice and some of his other chimeras were created in mockery of the Yamaraj, and other Charon, acting on a late, desperate hope of provoking a visitation. Even the mortal Charon are not so easily goaded, however.

The Fiend Storm

It was this drive to stir up greater and greater arcane currents which lead him down the road which caused the First North Sea Fiend Storm.

Transformation

Depictions of Vinewyltt's demise typically involve him leaping from his balcony atop vinthak's highest tower and plummeting beyond its total height, down into the valley beside the citadel, before rising again reborn and winged. Purportedly he slew a number of dire entities before ascending to the eye of the storm and disappearing. The storm dispersed shortly thereafter.